Hello.
The next thing we need to do is make it to a placard that can damage and kill our mushroom character.
If we head over to the Skeleton blueprint and open them up, the way we damage our mushroom is going
to be the exact way we damage on our skin tone.
So to save a bit of time, if we just copy all the notes here and then head over to the mushroom and
just paste them here, then go compile some things I'm going to transfer over.
So we're going to fix that now.
So for the health, just right click on this and create a health variable.
Then go compile and make it through.
The mushroom starts with five health.
For the enemy to just delete this.
Then just connect this and for the enemy damage, just right click and create this to a variable.
We can delete this set movement direction because for my range on me, I always want to face my character
and we've already set that up.
So I'll just hook this up here.
Then if we just go compile again.
I'm going to right click on this.
Is that viable and create the is that variable?
And for the time being, just disconnect this widget so you can select the open and select the target
to disconnect a node.
And just go compile.
Okay, before we do anything else, if we head over to the handle rotation and just delete this print
string.
And over at the hand of our station, we're going to have a branch.
We're only going to handle the rotation of our mushroom.
If they are not dead so under condition, Dragon is dead.
And as long as this condition is well, we'll handle our mushrooms rotation.
Next, we need to create a separate health bar for our mushroom character.
Some compile save and close this.
Then if we head over to the Widget Blueprint folder and just let the enemy health bar press control
C and control V and just rename this.
I call this all ranged enemy health bar.
Then, if we hadn't sat here.
I go to the golf?
Although this time just delete the scanned and reference and delete the variable here and create a new
variable and call this mushroom reference under variable type.
I'm going to look for the mushroom beep and set an object reference.
I'm just going to delete the notes here.
And then we go compile.
In my mushroom.
I didn't have a health variable, so I'm going to create a new rival and call it mass health.
And undesirable type.
I'm going to change this to be a flute.
Then we can play.
So right click for event.
We can play.
Then we can play.
I'm going to tell the game to set my max health to be whatever my health is.
So drag in the health.
And hook this up here.
If we compile and save this again and go over to our Range Enemy helper, we can now drag in mushroom
reference and get its health.
And we just want to divide this value by its max health.
So to drag and max health.
Connecting it here and then to here.
So now my mushroom character can have a health bar.
Or just compile and save this.
Then head over to my mushroom and I'll go add and the full widget.
All the space we're going to select screen and for the widget we want to select the ranged enemy helper.
Actually, you just changed this back to be world.
Just that I can visually see it and then rotate it so it looks correct.
So rotate it 90 degrees.
So that's how I want it to look in my own world.
Then I'm going to change it back to screen.
Then we head back to our event graph.
We want to track in widget, travel up here and get widget.
And from here we can up on the full course to ranged enemy.
And would promote this to available as we're going to reference this later.
Now I can come down here and then I'm going to hook up the widget.
And I'll hook up the widget here.
And we can go compile.
And the final thing we need to do is just drag in our as ranged enemy for reference, and we'll just
call the update whenever our enemy is damaged.
So call update helper and just make sure to plug this after we see our enemies health.
Okay, so now we can go compile and save.
There's one more thing we need to do to finish setting up the system, and that is to make the animations
inside of our mushroom animation.
So if we close this and go over to our mushroom animation blueprint, let's go to our new state machine
and just right click and look for jump.
We'll call this first jump node damaged and we're going to fire this node whenever our enemy is damaged.
So I'm just going to drag off here and look for animation state or select the state and rename this.
Take damage.
If I head inside here, I'm going to right click and play, take damage and just hook this up here.
And we'll connect this new to here in order to transition from my take damage to my idle state.
I'm going to head inside here, right click and the four time remaining.
Take damage.
And when the time remaining of this animation is less than 0.10, allow my mushroom to transition back
to its normal animation.
So look for less on the value of 0.1 and then we will hook this up here.
We're not going to create another node for when our mushroom dies.
Some of the right click.
Look for Trump and I'll call it mushroom death.
We can track Ock for animation and all this die.
If we hadn't sat here, we're going to play our mushroom DI animation.
So we'll play mushroom di.
Then we're going to drag off this animation and look for animation state and call this dead body.
If we had inside here, we're going to right click and we'll play that body and we'll just hook us up
here in order to transition to this animation.
We're going to wait for this animation to be less than 0.1 seconds before it's finished playing.
So we head inside here, right click and look for time remaining mushroom die.
We can drag up here and up for less than.
And put 0.1.
So when this animation has less than 0.1 seconds left, play will enter this animation state.
And now, if I head back to my BP here under the jump to Node, we need to make sure that everything
is spelled correctly.
So I call it damage.
So that's exactly the same.
I don't need to change it for when it dies.
I need it differently in the mushroom one.
So I call the mushroom death.
Someone copy this.
And just paste it here.
And I can go compile and I think I'll set up damage from my mushroom.
So I'm just going to close this and test this all out so it can play.
OC It looks like there are some issues.
So let's see.
So it looks like it's having problem referencing the mushroom ref.
So it's fading to reference the mushroom roof.
So if I go back to my mushroom blueprint here, after we create the enemy health reference, that's
a struggle.
And set mushroom reference.
And if we just shrug off it and look for self and connect this, we do here.
And one more thing.
I don't want my health part to show.
And I sat down with my enemy.
So we just let the widget and other details, if we look for visibility and just uncheck visible and
now go compile and go play.
If I turn into my enemy, you see it's health ball and it's launched back.
So there's actually one more thing I need to do, and that is give my mushroom some lateral friction
so it doesn't really fly through the air.
So I'm going to look for friction.
And here is fueling lateral friction.
And I put a value of 2.5.
I thought that worked well.
And now I can go compile play.
And now I can tell it to my mushroom character.
Let's just kill them to make sure everything works.
So I kill them.
They do that death animation and then it shows that dead body and then it disappears after 3 seconds.
So with this, we can now damage and hurt our mushroom.